



### PERSONAL INFORMATION

# Marius Pop



No.26, Bl.216, Ap.12, Ariesului Street, Alba County, Romania 510178

- +40749450066
- mrmariuspop@gmail.com
- www.linkedin.com/in/marivspop
- Skype live:mr.marius.pop

Sex Male | Date of birth 28/01/1997 | Nationality Romanian

JOB APPLIED FOR
POSITION
PREFERRED JOB
STUDIES APPLIED FOR
PERSONAL STATEMENT

## Java Software Developer

## WORK EXPERIENCE 16/10/2019 - Present

## Java Software Developer

Banca Transilvania SA, Str.George Baritiu 8, Cluj-Napoca, Romania

- Make design and architecture related decisions
- Handle new feature requests on time
- Promote TDD, coding guidelines and other best practices, including process improvements
- Perform code reviews for peers
- Provide analysis and design of the application
- Plan and execute all deployment of system features and monitor for successful integration, maintaining the system throughout its lifecycle
- Technologies used: Java8, JEE, Junit, Jenkins, Mockito, Maven/Gradle, Spring, Hibernate/JPA, Docker, Kubernetes, RESTful services, Swagger, Postman, OracleDB, SVN.

### 25/10/2019 - Present

### **Teaching Assistant**

Technical University of Cluj-Napoca, Strada George Barițiu 26-28, Cluj-Napoca, Romania

- Teaching Databases Laboratory
- Teaching Assembly Language Programming Laboratory

## 16/04/2018 - 10/10/2019

#### Java Software Developer

Accesa IT Systems SRL, Strada Constanta 12 Platinia, Cluj-Napoca, Romania

- Make design and architecture related decisions
- Handle new feature requests on time
- Promote TDD, coding guidelines and other best practices, including process improvements
- Perform code reviews for peers
- Provide analysis and design of the application
- Plan and execute all deployment of system features and monitor for successful integration, maintaining the system throughout its lifecycle
- Technologies used: Java8, JEE, Junit, Jenkins, Mockito, Maven/Gradle, Spring, Hibernate/JPA, Docker, Kubernetes, RESTful services, Swagger, Postman, PostgreSQL, GIT.



Marius Pop

euro*pass* 

25/06/2016 - 01/10/2016 25/07/2017 - 01/10/2017

## Inspector Supervisor

110 Sagamore Rd, Bolton Landing, NY 12814, USA

Coordinating a team of 30 housekeepers.

25/06/2016 - 01/10/2016 25/07/2017 - 01/10/2017

## Waiter

The Shack Restaurant 4948 Lake Shore Dr, Bolton Landing, NY 12814, USA

Hosting and waiting on customers

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

10/01/2015 - 10/07/2019

## Computer Science Student

Bachelor's Degree in computer science at Technical University of Cluj-Napoca

### 01/10/2019 - Present

## Information Technology Student

Master major: Information Technology in Economics

## PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s)

Romanian

## Other language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
B2	B2	B2	B2	B2

Italian

English

# Profile

Experienced java software engineer with full SDLC experience. Over 2 years of unique professional experience in best-in-class companies in ecommerce and financial industry. I also consider myself a fast learner, focused on delivery, committed to achieving high quality code with vast experience with agile and pair programming, a good communicator and strong team player, enjoying working with other people

## Communication skills

- Good communication and responsive to suggestion skills gained during volunteering activities in high school and college.
- Offering feedback and support skills to teammates



## Curriculum Vitae Marius Pop

#### Organisational / managerial skills

- Punctual and organized, having the capacity to complete the projects within the deadline.
- Teamwork skills gained during volunteering and team projects.
- Capable of setting objectives and priorities.
- Experience working in an Agile delivery model
- Problem solving skills
- Leadership (coordinating a team of 30 people)

#### Job-related skills

• Implementing and testing skills

#### Digital skills

SELF-ASSESSMENT						
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Safety	Problem solving		
Proficient User	Proficient User	Proficient User	Proficient User	Proficient User		

#### Driving licence

#### \_

#### ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

#### Certifications

Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer I

#### **Publications**

- Gabriel Cristian DRAGOMIR-LOGA, Marius POP, SMURD+. Medical Software, 2019 IEEE 15th International Conference on Intelligent Computer Communication and Processing, September 5 - 7, 2019, Cluj-Napoca, Romania.
- Marius POP, Gabriel Cristian DRAGOMIR-LOGA, Cloud Improvement of an Emergency Management System (SMURD+), 2019 IEEE International Conference on e-Health and Bioengineering, November 21-23, lasi, Romania.

## **Projects**

SMURD+.Medical Software

Leading development of the application. The system is meant to be installed on medical ambulances and tries to solve the problem of transporting a victim to the nearest hospital "to die". By analysing certain series of factors is takes a decision: which hospital the victim of an accident should be redirected to.

## ANNEXES

- Strong knowledge of Java Core
- Strong knowledge of OO design
- Experience writing test cases using JUnit and a follower of the TDD best practices
- Experience with Maven/Gradle and Git
- Experience with the following frameworks: Spring
- Experience with Hibernate/JPA, MyBatis.
- Experience with RESTful services
- Experience with Agile Methodologies (Scrum)
- Experience with relational database concepts and SQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle DB
- Experience with the full software development lifecycle (CI/CD)
- Experience in functional languages
- Willingness to rapidly learn new technologies and advocate for emerging technologies that will enhance the existing environment